[
    {
        "id": "01",
        "question" : "What is the primary purpose of a motherboard in a computer?",
        "options": [
            "To connect the computer to the internet",
            "To house the CPU, RAM, and other essential components",
            "To provide additional storage space",
            "All of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "To house the CPU, RAM, and other essential components"
    },
    {
        "id": "02",
        "question" : "What does the acronym BIOS stand for in computing?",
        "options": [
            "Basic Integrated Operating System",
            "Basic Input Output System",
            "Binary Integrated Operating System",
            "All of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "id": "03",
        "question" : "In a computer system, what is the role of an ALU (Arithmetic Logic Unit)?",
        "options": [
            " To manage network traffic",
            "To perform arithmetic and logical operations",
            " To store data permanently",
            " To control the display output"
        ],
        "answer": "To perform arithmetic and logical operations"
    },
    {
        "id": "04",
        "question" : "Which of the following is a volatile memory type?",
        "options": [
            "Hard Drive",
            "ROM",
            "SSD",
            "RAM"
        ],
        "answer": "RAM"
    },
    {
        "id": "05",
        "question" : "What is the function of a device driver in a computer system?",
        "options": [
            "To connect the computer to external devices",
            "To manage the power supply",
            "To facilitate communication between hardware and software",
            "To provide internet security"
        ],
        "answer": "To facilitate communication between hardware and software"
    },
    {
        "id": "06",
        "question" : "Which of the following is an example of a binary number system?",
        "options": [
            "Decimal",
            "Hexadecimal",
            "Binary",
            "Base-2"
        ],
        "answer": "Base-2"
    },
    {
        "id": "07",
        "question" : "What is the purpose of the file extension .exe in Windows operating systems?",
        "options": [
            " It indicates a text file",
            " It indicates a compressed file",
            "It indicates an executable file",
            "It indicates a graphic file"
        ],
        "answer": "It indicates an executable file"
    },
    {
        "id": "08",
        "question" : "What does RAID stand for, in the context of data storage?",
        "options": [
            "Random Array of Independent Disks",
            "Redundant Array of Independent Disks",
            " Redundant Access of Independent Drives",
            "Random Access of Internal Disks"
        ],
        "answer": "Redundant Array of Independent Disks"
    },
    {
        "id": "09",
        "question" : " Which protocol is used to transfer files between computers over a network?",
        "options": [
            "HTTP",
            "FTP",
            "SMTP",
            "TCP/IP"
        ],
        "answer": "FTP"
    },
    {
        "id": "10",
        "question" : "What is a “cache” in the context of computer memory?",
        "options": [
            " A type of external storage device",
            "A temporary storage area that speeds up data access",
            "A permanent memory storage medium",
            "A type of computer virus"
        ],
        "answer": "A temporary storage area that speeds up data access"
    }
]